SIYING CHEN

GIS Application Developer

INFO



Phone

614-531-8808



Email

siying chen@berkeley.edu



GitHub

flyingsiying.github.com

SKILLS

Web App Development

JavaScript, JQuery, D3, bootstrap, Java Spring Framework, R Shiny

Interactive Mapping

ArcGIS APIs, Mapbox APIs, Google Map APIs, Leaflet, OpenStreetMap, GeoJSON, WMS, WFS

GIS & Spatial Analysis

ArcMap, QGIS, ERDAS, Google Earth Engine, GIS programming in Python (GDAL, osgeo, scikit-learn), Spatial Simulation & Modeling via NetLogo

Database

Oracle SQL, Access

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering • 6/2017

University of California Berkeley

B.S. in GIS • 5/2016

The Ohio State University

PROFILE

I am a GIS enthusiast from Cal. I specialize in object oriented programing, web application development and database. My experience includes designing and implementing SQL database driven web applications; implementing both front-end and back-end aspects of dynamic and responsive applications using JQquery and Java Spring framework.

EXPERIENCE

GIS Application Developer

GEI Consultants • 6/2017 - now

- Built dozens of features for the existing Web GIS Applications using JQquery and ArcGIS API, which includes advanced map interactions, data representation and advanced query tools.
- Developed an Oracle SQL database driven web application to enable users to parse and search ArcGIS Rest Services.
- · Designed collections of robust GIS Algorithms in Java and Python, using GeoTools, JTS, OpenGIS APIs and ArcPy.
- & sgma.water.ca.gov/portal

GIS Application Developer

Street Nature Score • 8/2016 - 5/2017

Developed a web application based on Leaflet API and raster data processing with R, which enabled home seekers to look up the percentage of natural coverage at any given addresses in the US, resulting the interests from online real estate companies including Trulia and Zillow.



& streetnaturescore.com

Data Analyst

MyGreenCar, Berkeley Lab • 1/2017 - 5/2017

Developed a multinomial statistical model to analyze how people's travel habits and socioeconomic characteristic affect their behavior of buying a Plug-In Electric Vehicle (PEV), which helped the MyGreenCar Application to better match the greenest car with user's unique driving style.



& mygreencar.com